Peter Pawar

Unit 206, 1053-1055 Plenty Road, Kingsbury, Victoria, 3083 0452622086 pankaj.pawar1986@yahoo.com.au

Summary

A motivated and tech-savvy business consultant with around 6 years of experience working in various roles covering different aspects of business and Information Technology. Skills include web designing, database management, creative problem solving and project management. Able to communicate effectively with a team and very keen to develop more professional skills, such as computer networking.

Education

University of Mumbai

Bachelor's Degree

Mumbai, Maharashtra Graduated June 2009

I finished my Bachelor of Engineering in Information Technology from Sardar Patel Institute of Technology, which is affiliated to University of Mumbai. It was a four years course, where i learned and gained practical knowledge of latest concepts in Information Technology. Database Management, Object Oriented Programming, Software Testing are some of the subjects i learned during my course. Also, I was a part of my college's sports Team and participated in various extra curricular activities.

La Trobe University

Master's Degree

Bundoora, Victoria Graduated November 2014

I finished my Masters in Business Information Management and Systems from La Trobe University, Bundoora. The two years course helped in understand different aspects of Business and project management. We learned advanced concepts in Technology including Advanced Database Management, Project Management and Analytics.

Employment History

TELSTRA

NBN TRANSITION SPECIALIST

Docklands, Victoria March 2018 - Present

Key responsibilities:

- Analysing small business requirements and providing solution
- Understanding compatible NBN technologies to businesses
- Communicating with small business customers and helping them transition over to NBN network
- Understanding system requirements
- Creating reports and submitting them to manager
- Handling complex customer requests regarding NBN transition
- Communicating with case management team and providing feedback

IGA *MANAGER*

Northcote, Victoria August 2014 - March 2018

Key responsibilities:

- Managing and motivating a team to increase sales and ensure efficiency.
- Managing stock levels and making key decisions about stock control.

- Analysing sales figures and forecasting future sales.
- Analysing and interpreting trends to facilitate planning.
- Using information technology to record sales figures, analyse data and forward plan.
- Ensuring standards for quality, customer service and health and safety are met.
- Responding to customer complaints and comments.
- Organising special promotions, displays and events.
- Maintaining awareness of market trends in the retail industry.

Zeus Learning Senior Technical Specialist Mumbai, Maharashtra March 2010 - December 2012

After i finished my Bachelor Of Engineering in IT, I started working as "Technical specialist" (XML Integrator) for Zeus Learning PTY LTD, which is an e-learning firm based in Mumbai, India. I worked on several projects and learned different concepts in technology. One of the projects involved simulation of Microsoft office products like Excel, Word, Powerpoint. I used to create simulation webpages using HTML, XML and we used to upload them on client website.

Concepts i learned working in this role:

- 1. Web Designing
- 2. Software Testing
- 3. Project Management
- 4. MS-Office
- 5. HTML, XML, ASP.NET

Hobbies & Interests

I consider myself as a sports person. I love watching sports and on weekends, i go out and play badminton, cricket, table tennis with my friends. I love listening to music and trying different types of food. I like to socialise with my friends.

Professional Skills

html Advanced Advanced xml ms-office **Expert** Web Design **Intermediate** Database Design Competent Software QA Competent System Administration **Beginner** IT Project Management Competent ITIL Advanced PL/SQL Competent

References

Jamie Enright TELSTRA

Team Leader/Manager jamie.enright@team.telstra.com